Guide to the Leonid N. Stolovich papers M1624
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Leonid N. Stolovich papers
ca. 1940-2005
M1624
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
78.0 Linear feet 80 boxes; 14 boxes of books de-accn 7/2008; leaving 52 boxes of mss material and some newspapers.
The Leonid N. Stolovich papers include a wide range of correspondence with philosophers, literary authors, and scholars of literature and art, among others.
Stolovich, L. N. (Leonid Naumovich)
Conditions Governing Access note
The materials are open for research use.
Biography
Leonid Naumovich Stolovich (1929-2013) received his degrees from Leningrad University and was professor emeritus of the Philosophy Department of Tartu University in Estonia. He specialized in the fields of aesthetics, axiology and the history of philosophy. He is the author of more than forty books and 400 publications in 20 languages.
Acquisition Information
This collection was purchased by Stanford University, Special Collections in 2007.
Scope and Contents
The Stolovich papers are divided into 9 separate series: Personal Papers, Correspondence, Creative Works, Research Works by others, Art Work by others, Conference materials, Newspapers and magazines, Newspaper clippings, and Audiovisual materials.
Asmus, Ariadna Borisovna; Bernshtein, Boris Moiseevich; Blium, Rem Naumovich; Borev, Iurii Borisovich; Epstein, Mikhail; Funke, Gerhard; Ilves, Toomas Hendrik, 1953-; Losev, Aleksei Fedorovich; Lotman, Iurii Mikhailovich, 1922-1993; Magritz, Kurt; Medvedev, Roy Aleksandrovich, 1925-; Medvedev, Zhores Aleksandrovich, 1925-; Meri, Lennart; Mochalov, Lev Vsevolodovich; Pasternak, Boris Leonidovich, 1890-1960; Prozhogin, N.P.; Rebane, Jaan Karl, 1924-; Rozhdestvenskii, Robert, 1932-; Shteinberg, A.Z. (Aaron Zakharovich), 1891-1975; Slepakova, Nonna Mendelevna; Stolovich, L. N. (Leonid Naumovich); Tarkovskii, A.; Tsvetaeva, Marina; Tvardovskii, Aleksander T.; Wojnar, Irena; Woland, Gerd
- Series 1. Personal papers
  - Biographical material
    - School certificates, diplomas, permits, 1940-1943 (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - World War II: Documents, materials, clippings (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - Notebooks, random notes: 1940s-1950s (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Notebooks (Box 154, Folder 6)
    - Food rationing stamps (Box 66, Folder 8)
    - Studies in Leningrad University in 1950s (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - PhD thesis, 1955 (Box 113, Folder 8)
    - Appointment to the rank of associate professor, 1961 (Box 113, Folder 8)
    - Forms of employment, autobiographies (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Failure of employment in connection with Jewish identity (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Tartu University: work offers, notes, hiring (Box 113, Folder 1)
    - Tartu University: work offers, notes, hiring (Box 112, Folder 2)
    - Doctoral thesis, 1965 (Box 113, Folder 3)
    - Doctoral thesis, 1965 (Box 113, Folder 4)
    - Appointment to the rank of professor, 1967 (Box 113, Folder 3)
    - Reports on research work and publications (Box 113, Folder 5)
    - Reports on research work and publications (Box 113, Folder 6)
    - Reports on research work and publications (Box 113, Folder 7)
    - Articles about Stolovich in various publications, 1963-2003 (Box 156, Folder 1)
    - Diplomas, 1993-1996 (Box 112, Folder 9)
    - ID's and membership cards from various institutions and organizations (Box 159, Folder 13)
    - Travels abroad: Documents, Passport (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - Travels abroad: Brochures, guides etc. (Box 107, Folder 1)
    - Travels abroad: Brochures, guides etc. (Box 107, Folder 2)
    - Travels abroad: Visit to China, October 11-31, 2005 (Box 111, Folder 10)
    - Travels abroad: Visit to China, October 11-31, 2005: Correspondence, photographs (Box 128, Folder 8)
    - Professional activities: Department of Philosophy, Tartu University (Box 91, Folder 1)
    - Professional activities: Department of Philosophy, Tartu University (Box 91, Folder 2)
    - Professional activities: Department of Philosophy, Tartu University: Tруды по философии: Archives of the editorial board (Box 110, Folder 1)
    - Professional activities: Department of Philosophy, Tartu University: Tруды по философии: Archives of the editorial board (Box 110, Folder 2)
    - Professional activities: Tartu University: Sociological studies (Box 91, Folder 6)
    - Professional activities: Tartu University: Sociological studies (Box 91, Folder 7)
    - Professional activities: Teaching: Basis of Marxist-Leninist aesthetics: Syllabus (Box 155, Folder 3)
    - Professional activities: Teaching: Seminars on dialectical and historical materialism (Box 109, Folder 5)
    - Professional activities: Teaching: Seminars on dialectical and historical materialism (Box 90, Folder 6)
    - Professional activities: Teaching: Attendance books of seminars (Box 90, Folder 7)
    - Professional activities: Teaching: Lectures on aesthetics and attendance books (Box 116, Folder 5)
    - Professional activities: Teaching: Lectures on aesthetics and attendance books (Box 116, Folder 6)
    - Professional activities: Teaching: Lectures on aesthetics, slides (Box 148, Folder 1)
    - Professional activities: Teaching: Lectures on aesthetics, slides (Box 148, Folder 2)
    - Professional activities: Teaching: Lectures on aesthetics, slides (Box 148, Folder 3)
    - Professional activities: Teaching: Lectures on aesthetics, slides (Box 148, Folder 4)
    - Professional activities: Teaching: Lectures on aesthetics, slides (Box 148, Folder 5)
    - Professional activities: Teaching: Lectures on aesthetics, slides (Box 148, Folder 6)
    - Professional activities: Teaching: Lectures on aesthetics, slides (Box 148, Folder 7)
    - Professional activities: Teaching: Lectures on aesthetics, slides (Box 148, Folder 8)
    - Professional activities: Teaching: Lectures on aesthetics, slides (Box 148, Folder 9)
    - Professional activities: Teaching: Lectures on aesthetics, slides (Box 148, Folder 10)
    - Professional activities: Teaching: Lectures on aesthetics, slides (Box 148, Folder 11)
    - Professional activities: Teaching: Lectures on aesthetics, slides (Box 148, Folder 12)
    - Professional activities: Teaching: Lectures on aesthetics, slides (Box 148, Folder 13)
    - Professional activities: Ekspert Committee on the Social Sciences at Tartu University (Box 109, Folder 6)
    - Professional activities: Teaching: Lectures on aesthetics, slides (Box 148, Folder 14)
    - Professional activities: University of Marksism-Leninism at Tartu City Committee of Estonian Communist Party (Box 109, Folder 7)
    - Professional activities: Commitee of Aesthetics, Estonian Association of Philosophy (Box 110, Folder 3)
    - Professional activities: Commitee of Aesthetics, Estonian Association of Philosophy (Box 110, Folder 4)
    - Professional activities: Baltic Association for Aesthetics (Box 146, Folder 4)
    - Professional activities: Cooperation with research institutions, 1976-1982 (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Professional activities: The American Society for Aesthetics (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Professional activities: The American Society for Aesthetics (Box 106, Folder 11)
    - Professional activities: International Association for Aesthetics: Newsletters, correspondence (Box 92, Folders 3)
    - Professional activities: International Association for Aesthetics: Newsletters, correspondence (Box 92, Folders 4)
    - Professional activities: Comenius University in Bratislava, 1977-1978 (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - Professional activities: Comenius University in Bratislava, 1977-1978 (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - Professional activities: Comenius University in Bratislava, 1987 (Box 108, Folder 6)
    - Professional activities: Scientific Council on Problems of Aesthetics, Academy of Sciences of Soviet Union (Box 137, Folder 7)
    - Professional activities: The All-Union school of young scientists and specialists "Light and music", Kazan, Russia, September 20-30, 1987 (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Social and political activities: Memorial Foundation for Jewish Culture, 1994-2007 (Box 114, Folder 9)
    - Social and political activities: Tartu scientists against antisemitism, 1967 (Box 109, Folder 8)
    - Social and political activities: Tartu University, Department of Social Sciences: Communist Party Organization (Box 91, Folder 4)
    - Social and political activities: Tartu University, Department of Social Sciences: Communist Party Organization (Box 91, Folder 5)
    - Social and political activities: Estonian Writers' Union: Speeches (Box 123, Folder 5)
    - Leisure activities: Concerts, theatre performances, including programs, invitations etc. (Box 117, Folder 3)
    - Leisure activities: Concerts, theatre performances, including programs, invitations etc. (Box 117, Folder 4)
    - Leisure activities: Concerts, theatre performances, including programs, invitations etc. (Box 117, Folder 5)
    - Leisure activities: Concerts, theatre performances, including programs, invitations etc. (Box 118, Folder 1)
    - Leisure activities: Concerts, theatre performances, including programs, invitations etc. (Box 118, Folder 2)
    - Leisure activities: Philatelist materials: History of philosophy on postage stamps (Box 88, Folder 14)
    - Leisure activities: Philatelist materials: History of philosophy on postage stamps (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Leisure activities: Philatelist materials: History of philosophy on postage stamps (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - Leisure activities: Philatelist materials: History of philosophy on postage stamps (Box 89, Folder 3)
    - Leisure activities: Philatelist materials: History of philosophy on postage stamps (Box 89, Folder 4)
    - Leisure activities: Philatelist materials: History of philosophy on postage stamps, correspondence (Box 89, Folder 5)
    - Leisure activities: Correspondence on philatelic interests (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - Leisure activities: Correspondence on philatelic interests: Becker, Jacob (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - Leisure activities: Correspondence on philatelic interests: Devys, Jean (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - Leisure activities: Correspondence on philatelic interests: Lifsches, A. (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - Leisure activities: Correspondence on philatelic interests: Voiculescu, M. (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - Materials regarding a performance of the play "Cindarella's game" by Paul-Eerik Rummo (Box 92, Folder 1)
    - Materials regarding a performance of the play "Cindarella's game" by Paul-Eerik Rummo (Box 92, Folders 2)
    - 50th Birthday Anniversary: Greetings, clippings, photographs (Box 112, Folder 1)
    - 50th Birthday Anniversary: Greetings, clippings, photographs (Box 112, Folder 2)
    - 60th Birthday Anniversary: Greetings, clippings, photographs (Box 112, Folder 3)
    - 70th Birthday Anniversary: Greetings, clippings, photographs (Box 112, Folder 4)
    - 75th Birthday Anniversary: Greetings, clippings, photographs (Box 112, Folder 5)
    - Naum Borisovich Stolovich, father: Documents (Box 126, Folder 7)
    - Naum Borisovich Stolovich, father: Documents (Box 126, Folder 8)
    - Naum Borisovich Stolovich, father: Documents (Box 126, Folder 9)
    - Naum Borisovich Stolovich, father: Documents (Box 127, Folder 1)
    - Naum Borisovich Stolovich, father: Documents (Box 127, Folder 2)
    - Naum Borisovich Stolovich, father: Documents (Box 127, Folder 3)
    - Naum Borisovich Stolovich, father: Documents (Box 127, Folder 4)
    - Naum Borisovich Stolovich, father: Documents (Box 127, Folder 5)
    - Photographs: Early school years (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - Photographs: Childhood, youth (Box 126, Folder 5)
    - Photographs: Family members: Stolovich, Elizaveta Lazarevna, mother (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Photographs: Parents, grandparents, family members (Box 126, Folder 4)
    - Photographs: Graduates of the Faculty of Philosophy, State University in Leningrad (Flat-box 152, Folder 1)
    - Photographs: Graduates of the Physics Department, Tartu University, 1960 (Box 90, Folder 2)
    - Photographs: Faculty of Philosophy, Tartu University (Box 91, Folder 3)
    - Photographs: L.N. Stolovich and his olleagues philosophers (Box 90, Folder 4)
    - Photographs: L.N. Stolovich and his olleagues philosophers (Box 90, Folder 4)
  - Awards and Honors
    - Award of the newspaper "Sickle and Hammer", 1974; Award of Soviet Estonia, 1980; diplomas (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Diplomas, 1974-1982 (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Diplomas and honours, 1971-1980 (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - Stolovich's medals (Box 149, Folder 5)
  - Memorabilia
    - Pocket calendars, 1953, 1972-1979, 1986, 1988, 1993 (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Pocket calendars, 1962, 1966-1967, 1969, 1978, 1980, 1985 (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Pocket calendars, 1968, 1970, 1973, 1984 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Small notebooks (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Small notebooks (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Calendar for 1993 in Estonian and German (Box 135, Folder 4)
    - Various badges from conferences and congresses attended
    - Bag from the 6th World Congress of International Council for Central and East European Studies in Tampere, Finland (July 20 - August 3, 2000) (Flat-box 153, Object 1)
    - Tartu University, Department of Philosophy: Materials (Box 90, Folder 8)
    - Tartu University, Department of Philosophy: Bibliography cards from the library catalog (Box 129, Folder 5)
    - Tartu University, Department of Philosophy: Bibliography cards from the library catalog (Box 129, Folder 6)
    - Tartu University: Anniversary publications, pennant (Box 67, Folder 7)
    - Tallinna Polütehniline Instituut: Anniversary publications (Box 118, Folder 5)
    - Publishers' catalogs, which printed books by Stolovich (German and Slovak) (Box 155, Folder 4)
    - Business cards given to L.N. Stolovich (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - Business cards given to L.N. Stolovich (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - Business cards given to L.N. Stolovich (Box 74, Folder 9)
    - Business cards given to L.N. Stolovich (Box 74, Folder 10)
    - Autographs: Various material signed by celebrities (Box 149, Folder 1)
    - Autographs: Various material signed by celebrities (Box 149, Folder 2)
    - Autographs: Various material signed by celebrities (Box 149, Folder 3)
    - Autographs: Various material signed by celebrities (Box 149, Folder 4)
    - Invitations (Box 118, Folder 3)
    - Invitations (Box 118, Folder 4)
  - Personal files of contemporaries, including creative works
    - Adams, Vladimir (Valmar) (Box 111, Folder 2)
    - Aler, Jean (Box 132, Folder 11)
    - Aschenbrenner, Karl (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Asmus, Ariadna Borisovna and Pasternak, Boris Leonidovich (Box 111, Folder 1)
      Asmus, Ariadna Borisovna; Guberman, Igor; Pasternak, Boris Leonidovich, 1890-1960
    - Baumgarten, A. G. (Box 150, Folder 6)
      Prozhogin, N.P.; Woland, Gerd
    - Baumgarten, A. G. (Box 150, Folder 7)
    - Blium, Rem N. (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Blium, Rem N. (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Bogatkov, Stanislav V. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Borev, Iurii B (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Borev, Iurii B. (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Borev, Iurii B. (Box 133, Folder 11)
    - Borev, Iurii B.: his book "The Myths and beliefs of the 20th century" (Box 95, Folder 11)
    - Borev, Iurii B.: his book "The Myths and beliefs of the 20th century" (Box 95, Folder 12)
    - Burliuk, David (Box 132, Folder 2)
    - Chernyak, Irma (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Drankov, Vladimir l. (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Elshtein, Natan V. (Box 132, Folder 7)
    - Epsthein, Mikhail N (Box 29, Folder 4)
      Epstein, Mikhail
    - Fisher, John (Box 133, Folder 2)
    - Funke, Gerhard (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Funke, Gerhard (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - Funke, Gerhard (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - Gabinskii, Mark A. (Box 132, Folder 8)
    - Gdlian, T.; Ivanov N. (Box 88, Folder 13)
    - Goldberg, Vladislav (Box 114, Folder 10)
    - Goldberg, Vladislav (Box 115, Folder 1)
    - Guberman, Igor Mironovich (Box 111, Folder 7)
    - Ilves, Toomas H. (Box 29, Folder 4)
      Ilves, Toomas Hendrik, 1953-
    - Ingarden, Roman (Box 111, Folder 4)
    - Issakov, Segei (Flat-box 152, Folder 1)
    - IUrovskaia, E. P. (Box 120, Folder 5)
    - Jeu, Bernard (Box 132, Folder 9)
    - Kabur, Boris (Box 91, Folder 10)
    - Kagan, Moisei Samoilovich (Box 146, Folder 16)
    - Kaplinskii, Jaan (Box 91, Folder 10)
    - Karp, Poel (Box 132, Folder 5)
    - Kashtaner, Naum Mikhailovich (Box 150, Folder 3)
    - Khristov, Dmitrii I. (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Kogan, Lev N. (Box 91, Folder 10)
    - Kozina, Olesia (Box 91, Folder 10)
    - Kozina, Olesia (Box 91, Folder 11)
    - Kushner, Aleksandr (Box 132, Folder 4)
    - Kuznetsov, Artur (Flat-box 152, Folder 1)
    - Lennart, Meri (Box 111, Folder 6)
    - Lifshits, Mikhail A. (Box 132, Folder 1)
    - Loginova (Kazarian), Liudmila (Box 91, Folder 10)
    - Losskii, Nikolai O. (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Losev, Aleksei F. (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Losev, Aleksei F. (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Losev, Aleksei F. (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Losev, Aleksei F. (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Losev, Aleksei F. (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Losev, Aleksei F. (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Lotman, Iurii M. (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Lotman, Iurii M. (Box 100, Folder 6)
    - Lotman, Iurii M. (Box 100, Folder 7)
    - Lotman, Iurii M. (Box 100, Folder 8)
    - Lotman, Iurii M. (Box 100, Folder 9)
    - Lotman, Iurii M. (Box 100, Folder 10)
    - Lotman, Iurii M. (Box 100, Folder 11)
    - Lotman, Iurii M. (Box 101, Folder 3)
    - Lotman, Iurii M. (Box 101, Folder 4)
    - Lotman, Iurii M. (Box 101, Folder 5)
    - Lotman, Iurii M. (Box 101, Folder 6)
    - Lotman, Iurii M. (Box 101, Folder 7)
    - Magritz, Kurt (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Magritz, Kurt (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Magritz, Kurt (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Magritz, Kurt (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Magritz, Kurt (Box 90, Folder 1)
    - Makarev, Leonid, F. (Box 133, Folder 1)
    - Markiewicz, Henryk (Box 150, Folder 2)
      - Malevich, Oleg (Box 91, Folder 10)
    - Medevedev, Roy A., Medvedev, Zhores A. (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Medevedev, Roy A., Medvedev, Zhores A. (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - Medevedev, Roy A., Medvedev, Zhores A.: Photographs (Box 88, Folder 11)
    - Medevedev, Roy A., Medvedev, Zhores A.: Photographs (Box 88, Folder 12)
    - Medevedev, Roy A., Medvedev, Zhores A. (Box 117, Folder 1)
    - Medevedev, Roy A. (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - Medevedev, Roy A. (Box 88, Folder 2)
    - Medevedev, Roy A. (Box 88, Folder 3)
    - Medevedev, Roy A. (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - Medevedev, Roy A. (Box 88, Folder 5)
    - Medevedev, Roy A. (Box 88, Folder 6)
    - Medevedev, Roy A. (Box 88, Folder 7)
    - Medevedev, Roy A. (Box 88, Folder 8)
    - Medevedev, Roy A. (Box 88, Folder 9)
    - Medevedev, Roy A. (Box 88, Folder 10)
    - Medevedev, Roy A. (Box 94, Folders 10)
    - Medvedev, Zhores A. (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - Medvedev, Zhores A. (Box 87, Folder 6)
    - Medvedev, Zhores A. (Box 87, Folder 7)
    - Medvedev, Zhores A. (Box 87, Folder 8)
    - Medvedev, Zhores A. (Box 87, Folder 9)
    - Medvedev, Zhores A. (Box 87, Folder 10)
    - Medvedev, Zhores A. (Box 87, Folder 11)
    - Melikhov (Meilakhs), Aleksandr M. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Mikushevich, Vladimir Borisovich (Box 119, Folder 4)
    - Mikushevich, Vladimir Borisovich (Box 119, Folder 5)
    - Mikushevich, Vladimir Borisovich (Box 119, Folder 6)
    - Mochalov, Lev Vsevolodovich and Slepakova, Nonna Mendelevna (Box 110, Folder 5)
    - Mochalov, Lev Vsevolodovich and Slepakova, Nonna Mendelevna (Box 110, Folder 6)
    - Mochalov, Lev Vsevolodovich and Slepakova, Nonna Mendelevna (Box 110, Folder 7)
    - Mochalov, Lev Vsevolodovich and Slepakova, Nonna Mendelevna (Box 110, Folder 8)
      Mochalov, Lev Vsevolodovich; Slepakova, Nonna Mendelevna
    - Neiding, Veronika Leontevna (Box 119, Folder 9)
    - Nikolaev, Igor V. (Box 91, Folder 12)
    - Osborn, Harold (Box 133, Folder 5)
    - Paramonov, Boris: Radio Svoboda (Box 116, Folder 3)
    - Paramonov, Boris: Radio Svoboda (Box 116, Folder 4)
    - Prozhogin, Nikolai P. (Box 33, Folder 4)
    - Prozhogin, Nikolai P. (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - Puzis, Genrikh Borisovich (Box 119, Folder 7)
    - Rabinovich, Vadim (Box 91, Folder 10)
    - Rannit, Aleksis (Box 133, Folder 3)
    - Rotenstreich, Nathan (Box 133, Folder 4)
    - Ruuber, Georg Emilevich (Box 125, Folder 2)
    - Samoilov, David S. (Box 133, Folder 8)
    - Semenev, Gleb (Box 150, Folder 1)
    - Shestinskii, Oleg (Box 91, Folder 10)
    - Shteinberg, Aaron Zakharovich (Box 110, Folder 10)
      Rozhdestvenskii, Robert, 1932-; Shteinberg, A.Z. (Aaron Zakharovich), 1891-1975; Tarkovskii, A.; Tsvetaeva, M.
    - Smolianinov, I. F. (Box 119, Folder 8)
    - Solovev, Erik (Box 111, Folder 5)
    - Sosa, Rafael (Box 150, Folder 5)
      Tvardovskii, Aleksander T.
    - Stolovich, Andres Leonidovich (Box 112, Folder 6)
    - Stolovich, Andres Leonidovich (Box 112, Folder 7)
    - Stolovich, Andres Leonidovich (Box 112, Folder 8)
    - Tatarkiewicz, Wladyslaw (Box 111, Folder 3)
    - Tugarinov, Vasilii P. (Box 133, Folder 7)
    - Vacchi, Sergio (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Vereiskaia, Elena N. (Box 133, Folder 6)
    - Volodin, Aleksandr (Box 132, Folder 3)
    - Vysokosova (Karklina), Lilianna Dmitrievna (Box 116, Folder 1)
    - Wolandt, Gerd (Box 132, Folder 10)
    - Zhovtis, Aleksandr L. (Box 132, Folder 6)
    - Unknown author (Box 133, Folder 9)
    - Materials on M. Tsvetaeva, N. Glazkov, A. Tarkovskii, V. Sokolov, L. Martynov, V. Lugovskii, R. Rozhdestvenskii, A. Tvardovskoii, G. Sangir (Box 14, Folders 5)
- Series 2. Correspondence
  - Family members
    - Stolovich, Elizaveta Lazarevna, mother: letters from family and friends (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Stolovich, Elizaveta Lazarevna, mother: letters from family and friends (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Stolovich, Elizaveta Lazarevna, mother: letters from family and friends (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Stolovich, Elizaveta Lazarevna, mother: letters from family and friends (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - Stolovich, Elizaveta Lazarevna, mother: letters from family and friends (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Stolovich, Elizaveta Lazarevna, mother: letters from family and friends (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Stolovich, Elizaveta Lazarevna, mother: letters from family and friends (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Stolovich, Elizaveta Lazarevna, mother: letters from family and friends (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Stolovich, Elizaveta Lazarevna, mother: letters from family and friends (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - Stolovich, Elizaveta Lazarevna, mother: letters from family and friends (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - Stolovich, Elizaveta Lazarevna, mother: letters from family and friends (Box 69, Folder 8)
    - Stolovich, Elizaveta Lazarevna, mother: letters from family and friends (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Stolovich, Elizaveta Lazarevna, mother: letters from family and friends (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Stolovich, Elizaveta Lazarevna, mother: letters from family and friends (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - Stolovich, Elizaveta Lazarevna, mother: letters from family and friends (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - Stolovich, Elizaveta Lazarevna, mother: letters from family and friends (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - Stolovich, Elizaveta Lazarevna, mother: letters from L.N. Stolovich (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Stolovich, Elizaveta Lazarevna, mother: letters from L.N. Stolovich (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Stolovich, Elizaveta Lazarevna, mother: letters from L.N. Stolovich (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - Stolovich, Elizaveta Lazarevna, mother: letters from L.N. Stolovich (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Stolovich, Elizaveta Lazarevna, mother: address book (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - Stolovich, Elizaveta Lazarevna, mother (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Stolovich, Inna, daughter (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Stolovich, Inna, daughter (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Stolovich, Andres, son (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Letters to Leonid Stolovich and his family (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Letters to Leonid Stolovich and his family (Box 57, Folder 5)